We have seen parts of a function and how they
work. Let’s put these parts together and define
our own function. As we define a function, pay
close attention to the keyword used to define
a function, as it’s not the word, function, as
is the case in many other languages. To start,
I have a blank file, except for a comment on line
1 explaining the function we are about to build,
which will multiply a score and multiplier
and return the result. The keyword to define
a function is def, short for definition. I
will type that keyword, def, on line 2. Next,
we need a name for the function. I will name
this calculate_score, with an underscore between
the two words. Next, we need to determine if the
function will take arguments, variables that will
be used in a condition, calculation, or both.
Since this function will multiply two numbers,
I will add two arguments in parentheses: score and
multiplier. Then, as with many other code blocks,
I will add a colon to the end of the line.
Most functions will want to return a value to
be used later in code. As we saw in the previous
topic, the return keyword returns a value that
can be used later in code. Any code running
within a function must be indented under the
def statement. For this example, we only need one
line to return the score times the multiplier. To
call this function, I will type, on line 5, the
name of the function, and then, in parentheses,
the score and the multiplier, wrapped inside
of a print statement. I will run this code,
and we will see the result. Next, let’s see
the main benefit of functions. I will copy
the print statements calling the function,
change the numbers, and rerun the code. The
same block of code is now run twice. One could
run a function thousands of times if needed,
and if the function changes, the code for
the function only needs to be changed once,
thus increasing the efficiency of code
and helping to prevent errors in code.